Jerrell Nolen

Game Developer

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Game Developer with 3+ years of experience working on indie teams working towards developing small titles with skills in Narrative Development as well as Level Design. Experienced in Unity Engine, Adobe Suite (including Premier, Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign), as well as using the programming languages C#, C++, Python, and JS. Worked as Scrum Master on development of Installation 23, using the Agile Development format to assist team in reaching short term, as well as long term goals, as well as shifting project goals during early development in order to keep timeline as realistic as possible.

CONTACT



(773)-575-2066



nolen.jerrell@hotmail.com

PORTFOLIO

http://jerrelInolen.net

EDUCATION

BACHELORS'S DEGREE

BA in Game Design: Game Development Columbia College Chicago 2017 – 2021

EXPERTISE

SOFTWARE

Adobe Suite(Photoshop, Illustrator, Premier), Unity3D

WEB/PROGRAMMING

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, C#, C++

SKILLS

Communicative Leadership
Team Oriented Dependable
Adaptability Collaborative
Problem-Solver Open-Minded
Creative Eager to learn

Attentive to Detail

EXPERIENCE

GAME DESIGNER: Installation 23

Columbia College Chicago / 2019 - Present

- Created the procedurally generated levels used within the title Installation 23 using the Unity Engine's built in tile system
- Created Basic Systems for combat and progression in the game, as well as pacing through the levels
- Created Dialogue system for game to allow player to get information on their goal, and further immerse them within the world
- Created scope of game, fixing it to fit within the given theme from project lead while still being fun and interesting

GAME DESIGNER: Project Steampunk

Kappa Korp / June 2017 - Present

- Crafted the lore and world of Project Steampunk, including a historical timeline and major characters.
- Headed story development creating a clear line of growth for the world and characters to showcase the universe to the players
- Created Quests in a screenplay format in order to make clear the vision intended for what needs to be occurring on screen and what the player is to learn from the quest
- Programmed basic combat movement system for player
- Created basic systems for game using easy to read documents

CARPENTRY

Freelance / 2010 - 2017

- Assisted in several independent jobs including the refurbishing of multiple houses in the Detroit area.
- Projects consisted of changing carpets, putting up walls, laying down tiles, painting, lawn care (trimming bushes, mowing lawn, raking leaves, etc), and replacing doors and windows